# **Monika Patel**

I'm a self-motivated Front-End Developer & Web Developer who loves to learn and create. I have 3+ years of experience and feel that I would be a great asset to any development or design team. I strive to deliver quality work through focused research and endeavor to be at the edge of emerging technology.

# **Professional Experience**

Feb 2015 - Present

## Scantech/Solution Dynamics - .NetDeveloper

Working within an Agile development environment as a .Net Developer for the web and windows applications development and maintenance. Role established UI and component guidelines to ensure the clear direction & alignment of a consistent UI for the end users. Worked closely with other dev-team leaders and sales to bring a consistent vision for the applications.

- 01. Produce and maintain data digitalizing software applications.
- **02.** Manage UI guidelines within the Application Development team.
- **03.** Understanding of repeatable automated processes for building the application, testing it, documenting it, and deploying it at scale.

Aug - Oct 2014

## ACE cars rental — Front End Developer

I was part of a small development team, responsible for all front-facing aspects of ACE rental's sites. Worked on Google analytics, tag manager & AdWords for specifically New Zealand site.

#### **FLUENT WITH**

- Photoshop CS6
- CorelDraw X7
- HTML5
- CSS3, grid and flexbox, bootstrap
- Java Script, jQuery
- VB.Net
- C#
- WF/WCF/WPF
- MS SQL Server

#### **FAMILIAR WITH**

- Adobe Illustrator
- Reacts
- WordPress

- **01.** Re-Built & Maintained many user-friendly, content-managed websites using bootstrap and jQuery frameworks.
- **02.** Became more focused on online booking forms across different mobile devices, and how to enrich small screen web experiences.

Jan 2013 - Mar 2014

#### Tatvasoft Ltd — WebDeveloper

Started as Intern and eventually became a responsible part of team. I worked in small development team, responsible for all front-facing aspects of insurance service site for United states client.

- **01.** Worked with Senior developers, designers and insurance service provider to understand a brief of insurance terms.
- **02.** Delivered insurance website for the www.insurox.com

## Education

Aug 2009 - Feb 2013

## **Charotar University of Science and Technology**

Bachelor of Computer science with GPA 8.42/10

- Sliver Strip
- SASS & LESS
- ES6
- -MVC

#### Others

 Language: Fluent English speaker with Hindi language proficiency.

#### Hobbies/Interests

 I am fiend of Succulents. To enlarge my succulent collections, I am part of Auckland Succulents and Cactus society.

#### Contact Info

- monikapatel.it@outlook.com
- in/monikapatelit
- +64 221 37 9800